<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>The Curious Coder</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>This is My New Hugo Site</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>This is a JavaScript world! 5 Languages that compile to JS</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/this-is-a-js-world/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/this-is-a-js-world/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/transpilation_diagram.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>If you are a web developer you probably have… developed a love-and-hate relationship with JavaScript.
While it is a feature-rich and constantly evolving language, it has some limitations. Especially when it comes to complex applications it may fall short.
A popular solution chosen among developers is using a different language that gets compiled to JavaScript. This can be achieved with a tool called transpiler. A transpiler is essentially a compiler that transforms a language’s code to another high-level language code (not an assembly language).]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to start with Deep Learning</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/08/start-with-dl/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/08/start-with-dl/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/Deep-Neural-Network-architecture.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Embracing the hype Nowadays, everyone is talking about Artificial Intelligence. Whether understands it or not. This discussion essentially comes down to two terms: Machine Learning and Deep Learning.
Machine learning (ML) is the study of computer algorithms that improve automatically through experience and by the use of data.
Deep Learning is a type of Machine Learning based on Artificial Neural Networks with multiple layers.
Artificial neural networks (ANNs) are computing systems inspired by the biological neural networks that constitute animal brains.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Learn You a Functional Programming for Great Good!</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/learn-you-a-fp/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/learn-you-a-fp/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/fp.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Level of knowledge required: This article requires some programming background to be fully understood.
Introduction I am sure you have noticed the silly syntax in this article&rsquo;s title. It is inspired by a popular introductory book for the Haskell language, called “Learn You a Haskell for Great Good!” [1]. Which could probably be perceived as “Learn Haskell for great benefit”. Haskell is one of the so-called purely functional programming languages. Or more precisely, almost purely functional.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to be social in the terminal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/06/how-to-be-social-in-the-terminal/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 21:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/06/how-to-be-social-in-the-terminal/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/social.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Online social networks Whoever knows me personally is aware that I am not the biggest fan of social networks. Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, I was always involved with them. Understanding social networks was also part of my research interests for a quite long time. But my relationship with them was always a love and hate one.
In this blog, I&rsquo;m going to talk a lot about this relationship.
In this post, though I will diverge from this discussion.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Computer Science as a Medicine</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/06/cs-as-a-medicine/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/06/cs-as-a-medicine/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/cs.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Introduction It was November 2019 and I was on the plane flying to another country. I was going to move there. This was something far outside my comfort zone, and I was a bit terrified. I knew that I would have to deal with a stream of new challenges, and this made me a bit anxious.
I started reading a computer science book I had bought for my trip. The title was ”Algorithms to Live By”.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to live your digital life in a terminal : Introduction</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/06/how-to-live-your-digital-life-in-a-terminal-introduction/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 21:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/06/how-to-live-your-digital-life-in-a-terminal-introduction/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/zueyl-nt1x.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The bloated web I recall a few years ago me sharing Mozilla’s dream for the web. The web was on its way to become the main platform for internet users. And that was supposed to be a good thing, due to its openness and the freedom that it was providing. But freedom and control are relative concepts.
Web now has become bloated with unnecessary code, advertisements, pop-ups, comments and recommendation systems that are trying to mine our data and keep us hooked in their user interfaces by providing us with constants hits of dopamine.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Why I occasionally go off the grid</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/why-i-occasionally-go-off-the-grid/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 21:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/why-i-occasionally-go-off-the-grid/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/7rmmnhwrb.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A great day for scrolling It’s a great day outside. The sun is up.
The weather is good and you are enjoying this relaxing day. Suddenly, you hear a beeping sound. It’s your phone notifying you of a new message. You text back and you put your phone back in your pocket.
Another sound. Yay! Someone new followed you on Twitter. “Let’s see who this is!” You tell yourself. You open the app and start scrolling.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Why is Fake News Spread so Hard to Stop?</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/why-is-fake-news-spread-so-hard-to-stop/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 21:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/why-is-fake-news-spread-so-hard-to-stop/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/vxaimuibyt.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Some History Disinformation is not a recent issue. As Guardian columnist Natalie Nougayr`ede has observed: ”The use of propaganda is ancient, but never before has there been the technology to so effectively disseminate it” [1].
Misinformation, disinformation, and propaganda have been features of human communication since at least the Roman times [2]. However, the invention of the Gutenberg printing press in 1493 dramatically amplified the dissemination of disinformation and misinformation, and it ultimately delivered the first large-scale news hoax - ’The Great Moon Hoax’ of 1835.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
